<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Blog on Dental Stories</title><link>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/</link><description>Recent content in My Blog on Dental Stories</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 05:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dentalstories.ml/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Dental Scaling?</title><link>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/what-is-dental-scaling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/what-is-dental-scaling/</guid><description>Gum disease is a serious issue. About 47% of adults aged 30 years and older seem to suffer from periodontitis. So let us look at the most common treatment method here.</description></item><item><title>Is Chocolate That Bad for My Teeth?</title><link>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/is-chocolate-that-bad-for-my-teeth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 20:55:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/is-chocolate-that-bad-for-my-teeth/</guid><description>How would you feel if I tell you all these chocolates you eat can help you to reduce caries development in your mouth?&amp;hellip;YES..! I would feel the same because who doesn’t like chocolates!
Chocolate derived from cocoa plant contains theobromine (alkaloid) have been found to be anticariogenic in nature. theobromine can be found more in the dark chocolate than the milk chocolate.
Researchers have been working on various studies for the same and found that theobromine in the cocoa husk given an apatite-forming medium helps in enhancing the remineralisation of the enamel (outer structure of the tooth).</description></item><item><title>Busting myths - Dental Caries</title><link>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/busting-myths-dental-caries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/busting-myths-dental-caries/</guid><description>According to the World Health Organization (WHO) globally it is estimated that 2.3 billion people suffer from caries of permanent teeth and more than 5.3 million children suffer from caries of the primary teeth.
&amp;ldquo;No no my teeth never hurt I don&amp;rsquo;t need to go to the dentist&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I have a brown spot on teeth but its alright unless its hurting&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Milk teeth are not important anyways they are going to fall out&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Only sugar cause carries&amp;rdquo; We all have heard these statements now and then but ever actually looked out for finding the truth?</description></item><item><title>When Should You Start Brushing</title><link>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/when-should-you-start-brushing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/when-should-you-start-brushing/</guid><description>Do you remember when you started brushing on your own? Studies have shown that brushing should be started as soon as the baby has started feeding.
Here are some measures to maintain a good oral hygiene for the child:
• Even before they have any teeth wipe the gums with a warm, wet gauze piece every day. It will clean off the any sugary product left on gums.
• When tooth appears above the gum line i.</description></item><item><title>Dental Care Tips at Home</title><link>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/dental-care-tips-at-home/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 20:46:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dentalstories.ml/blog/dental-care-tips-at-home/</guid><description>Amidst the world wide pandemic crisis everything is disturbed. In such a situation it is important to look after yourself and keep a healthy body as well as a healthy mind.
The dental offices have been shut in various countries. Regular visits to the dentist have been hampered. So taking care of the oral hygiene is very much important by being at home.
Following tips can be followed to maintain a good oral hygiene:</description></item></channel></rss>